<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Camerata Musica - 2015-2016</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/feeds/2015-2016.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://cameratamusica.com/</id><updated>2016-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Simphonie</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/simphonie.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2016-04-23:/simphonie.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/simphonie.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/Simphonie200.png" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;April 23 at 8:00pm in the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingrid Matthews, baroque violin &lt;br&gt;
Jeffrey Cohan, baroque flute &lt;br&gt;
Hans-Jürgen Schnoor, harpsichord …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/simphonie.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/Simphonie200.png" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;April 23 at 8:00pm in the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingrid Matthews, baroque violin &lt;br&gt;
Jeffrey Cohan, baroque flute &lt;br&gt;
Hans-Jürgen Schnoor, harpsichord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;table width="800" align="center"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center" colspan="2"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Program&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Trio Sonata in G Major, BWV 1027 and 1039&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Johann Sebastian Bach&lt;/b&gt; (1685-1750)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td colspan="2" class="smallindent"&gt;(originally for viola da gamba and obbligato harpsichord, or two flutes and continuo)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sonata in G Major for violin and continuo, BWV 1021&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bach&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sonata in B Minor, BWV 1030&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bach&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td colspan="2" class="smallindent"&gt;(flute and obbligato harpsichord)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="height:10px"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="height:10px"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td colspan="2" class="center"&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;div class="smallheading"&gt;Intermission
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Musical Offering Trio Sonata in C Minor, BWV 1079&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bach&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td colspan="2" class="smallindent"&gt;(originally for flute, violin and continuo)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Trio Sonata in G Major, BWV 1019 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bach&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td colspan="2" class="smallindent"&gt;(originally for violin and harpsichord obbligato)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Artiest Bio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ingrid Matthews&lt;/b&gt; has long been established as one of the leading baroque violinists of her generation. She founded the &lt;a href="http://www.seattlebaroque.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Seattle Baroque Orchestra&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="http://www.byronschenkman.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Byron Schenkman&lt;/a&gt; in 1992, and served as Music Director until stepping down from that position in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthews won first prize in the 1989 Erwin Bodky International Competition for Early Music, and since that time has performed extensively around the world with numerous period-instrument ensembles. She has served as concertmaster for orchestras such as the &lt;a href="http://www.nycollegium.org/" target="_blank"&gt;New York Collegium,&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href="http://www.bemf.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Boston Early Music Festival Orchestra,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.musicaangelica.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Musica Angelica&lt;/a&gt; (Los Angeles); and has appeared as a guest director and soloist with many others including the New York Collegium, the &lt;a href="http://www.brandenburg.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Australian Brandenburg Orchestra,&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href="http://www.magnoliabaroque.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Magnolia Baroque Festival Orchestra&lt;/a&gt; (Winston-Salem, NC), &lt;a href="http://www.newtrinitybaroque.org/" target="_blank"&gt;New Trinity Baroque&lt;/a&gt; (Atlanta), the &lt;a href="http://www.bachsinfonia.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Bach Sinfonia&lt;/a&gt; (Washington DC), Les Idees Heureuses (Montreal), the Indianapolis Baroque Orchestra, and the Victoria Symphony. For close to a decade she was first violinist of the ensemble La Luna, which specialized in 17th-century music, touring and recording to great critical acclaim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthews' career as a chamber musician has taken her to such venues as the Frick Collection (New York), the Boston Early Music Festival, the Berkeley Festival, Netwoork voor Oude Muziek (the Netherlands), the Getty Center (LA), the Pittsburgh Renaissance and Baroque Society, Early Music Vancouver, Woodstock Concerts, the Cambridge Society for Early Music, the Newberry Library (Chicago), CBC-Toronto, the San Francisco Early Music Society and the Library of Congress, among many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthews has won international critical acclaim for a &lt;a href="http://www.ingridmatthews.com/music/discography.html" target="_blank"&gt;discography&lt;/a&gt; ranging from the earliest solo violin repertoire through the Sonatas and Partitas of J.S. Bach. The latter recording was named by Third Ear's Classical Music Listening Companion as "the finest complete set of these works," and the critic for American Record Guide writes "this superb recording is my top recommendation for this music… on either modern or period instruments."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingrid Matthews has served on the faculties of the University of Toronto, the University of Washington, Indiana University, the University of Southern California in Los Angeles, the &amp;lt;a href="http://www.longy.edu/" target="_blank"International Baroque Institute at Longy,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.amherstearlymusic.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Amherst Early Music;&lt;/a&gt; and has given master classes in baroque repertoire and style at numerous colleges and universities.  She is currently on the faculty of &lt;a href="http://www.cornish.edu/" target="_blank"&gt;Cornish College of the Arts in Seattle.&lt;/a&gt;  Ingrid Matthews is a graduate of Indiana University, where she studied with &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Josef_Gingold" target="_blank"&gt;Josef Gingold&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://info.music.indiana.edu/sb/page/normal/898.html" target="_blank"&gt;Stanley Ritchie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingrid Matthews is also known as Ingrid Matthews Olson. A passionate life-long interest in the visual arts has led her to amass an eclectic training in various techniques, and her &lt;a href="F:\CamerataMusica2015-2016\Workups\Simphonie\Macintosh HD:\Users\general\Desktop\art\index.html" target="_blank"&gt;paintings&lt;/a&gt; have been shown in group and solo exhibitions in Seattle and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Borealis Wind Quintet</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/borealis-wind-quintet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2016-03-19:/borealis-wind-quintet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/borealis-wind-quintet.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/Borealis200.jpg" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;March 19 at 8:00pm in the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith Bonner, Flute &lt;br&gt;
Tamar Beach Wells, Oboe &lt;br&gt;
Kathryn Taylor, Clarinet &lt;br&gt;
Dan …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/borealis-wind-quintet.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/Borealis200.jpg" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;March 19 at 8:00pm in the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith Bonner, Flute &lt;br&gt;
Tamar Beach Wells, Oboe &lt;br&gt;
Kathryn Taylor, Clarinet &lt;br&gt;
Dan Culpepper, French Horn &lt;br&gt;
Wayne Hileman, Bassoon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by Andrew Fingland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;table width="800" align="center"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center" colspan="2"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Program&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Suite, Op. 57&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Charles Lefebvre&lt;/b&gt; (1843-1917)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Three Summer Dances&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Joseph Turrin&lt;/b&gt; (b. 1947)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lincolnshire Posy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Percy Grainger&lt;/b&gt; (1882-1961)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="height:10px"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="height:10px"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;td colspan="2" class="center"&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;div class="smallheading"&gt;Intermission
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Variations sur un thčme libre, Op.42 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Eugčne Bozza&lt;/b&gt; (1905-1991)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Three Moods&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Andrey Rubtsov&lt;/b&gt; (b. 1982)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Potpourri Fantastico&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Giulio Briccialdi&lt;/b&gt; (1818-1881)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Artiest Bio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Borealis Wind Quintet&lt;/strong&gt;, nominated for a 2006 Grammy Award in the Chamber Music Category, is acclaimed as one of America's preeminent chamber ensembles. The highest musical integrity, irresistible energy and five-fold charisma distinguish Borealis in the chamber music field. Audiences love their exquisite programming that includes the finest of the classics, engaging commissioned works, opera arias and works for piano and winds. The Washington Post praised their "sensitive collaborations that have a sophisticated and cosmopolitan air." Peter G. Davies of the New York Times described one concert as "a polished, elegantly turned performance...each work received lively, expert and musicianly treatment by this skilled and exceptionally talented chamber group." Joseph Horowitz, also of the New York Times describes "lively communicative readings...the performance was a scintillating one." The Philadelphia Inquirer writes, "They demonstrated the sort of rapport that characterizes the very best chamber playing."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keith Bonner&lt;/strong&gt;, flutist, has performed in a wide variety of ensembles, including symphony and opera orchestras, Broadway pits, movies and television. Mr. Bonner is currently principal flute of the Riverside Symphony, and will be performing the Nielsen Flute Concerto with them this spring at Lincoln Center, NYC. He has performed with the Symphony orchestras of New Jersey and Stamford, CT as well as the Orchestra of St. Luke’s, New York City Ballet, American Symphony Orchestra and the New York Symphonic Ensemble. Mr. Bonner can be heard in the orchestra of the 25th anniversary production of Les Miserables now on Broadway. He is on the faculty of Brooklyn College and Special Music School in New York City. He has degrees from the Manhattan School and the Cleveland Institute of Music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamar Beach Wells&lt;/strong&gt; is principal oboist with the Greater Bridgeport Symphony and has played with the Hartford Symphony Orchestra, the American Composers Orchestra, the Berkshire Bach Ensemble and the Westchester Symphony. Ms. Wells has been a member of the Springfield Symphony and the Goodspeed Opera, and has toured nationally with Andrea Bocelli. In addition to the oboe, she plays the English horn, oboe d’amore and bass oboe and frequently collaborates with vocalists, choruses and other artists in diverse settings ranging from traditional solo performances to recording sessions, pop to opera. She has also given hundreds of childrens’ concerts with the Hartford Symphony’s  inner city outreach program. Ms. Wells has been on the faculty of the Hartt School and the University of Connecticut.  She is a voting member of the Grammy Foundation. Ms. Wells holds Bachelor’s degrees in performance and education from the Hartt School and a Masters degree from the Juilliard School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kathryn Taylor&lt;/strong&gt;, clarinet, has performed across the US as a chamber and orchestra musician as well as a soloist. A resident of Connecticut, she is principal clarinetist of the Greater Bridgeport Symphony. She performs with the Stamford, New Haven and Hartford Symphonies. Ms. Taylor has performed in several festivals including the Aspen Music Festival in Colorado, the Spoleto Festival in Charleston, SC, the Windham Festival in New York and the Newport Festival in Rhode Island. She has toured Europe as principal clarinetist with the American Symphonietta and performed in the orchestra of Beauty and the Beast on Broadway. Ms. Taylor attended the Juilliard School where she studied with the legendary Leon Russianoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Culpepper&lt;/strong&gt; is a very active freelance horn player in New York City. He performs with the New York City Ballet, New York Pops, Little Orchestra Society, Pitstop Players and at Radio City Music Hall. Mr. Culpepper's career has been both diverse and eclectic. He has performed or recorded with Frank Sinatra, Barbara Streisand, Elton John, James Taylor, Beyoncé, Pavarotti, Sting and Yo-Yo Ma among others. He has recorded numerous film soundtracks, TV and radio commercials and live broadcasts. On Broadway Mr. Culpepper has been a member of the orchestras of Les Miserables, Miss Saigon and is currently principal horn of Phantom of the Opera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wayne Hileman&lt;/strong&gt;, bassoon, has performed with many orchestras including the New Haven, Stamford, American and Westchester Symphonies, and appeared as a chamber player, soloist, or as continuo at many venues, including the Pro-Arte, Windham, Alliance Artist, and New England Bach Festivals. In addition, he is an audio engineer, restoring historic recordings for major labels, producing live concerts for NPR, editing and mastering new releases for many classical artists, and is a voting member of the Recording Academy (the Grammys). In 2006 he co-founded Candlewood Digital, a high-end recording company dedicated to the needs of classical musicians. Mr. Hileman holds degrees from Potsdam College and Yale University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joanne Rile Artists Management&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
93 Old York Rd., Jenkintown Commons 222, Jenkintown, PA 19046 &lt;br&gt;
(215) 885-6400 &lt;a href="mailto:artists@rilearts.com"&gt;artists@rilearts.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="www.rilearts.com"&gt;www.rilearts.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Trio Tremonti</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/trio-tremonti.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-02-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2016-02-27:/trio-tremonti.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/trio-tremonti.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/Tremonti200.png" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;February 27 at 8:00pm in the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saul Bitrán, Violin &lt;br&gt;
Jan Müller-Szeraws, Cello &lt;br&gt;
Sally Pinkas, Piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.triotremonti.com/"&gt;Trio Tremonti …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/trio-tremonti.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/Tremonti200.png" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;February 27 at 8:00pm in the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saul Bitrán, Violin &lt;br&gt;
Jan Müller-Szeraws, Cello &lt;br&gt;
Sally Pinkas, Piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.triotremonti.com/"&gt;Trio Tremonti Web Site&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;table width="800" align="center"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center" colspan="2"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Program&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Círculo, Fantasia Para Piano, Violin y Violoncello, Op. 91&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Joaquín Turina&lt;/b&gt; (1882-1949)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Trio no. 2 in G minor, Op. 26 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Antonín Dvorák&lt;/b&gt; (1841-1904)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="height:10px"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="height:10px"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;td colspan="2" class="center"&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;div class="smallheading"&gt;Intermission
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Trio pour Piano, Violon et Violoncelle&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Maurice Ravel&lt;/b&gt; (1875-1937)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Artiest Bio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trio Tremonti presents three internationally-acclaimed artists, joined together with a deep musical bond: Mexican-born violinist &lt;strong&gt;Saul Bitrán&lt;/strong&gt;, Chilean cellist &lt;strong&gt;Jan Müller-Szeraws&lt;/strong&gt;, and Israeli pianist &lt;strong&gt;Sally Pinkas&lt;/strong&gt;. Now in its third year as Ensemble-in-Residence at the Cambridge School of Weston, Trio Tremonti members are also Artists-in-residence at the College of the Holy Cross in Massachusetts (Bitrán and Müller-Szeraws), and the Hopkins Center in New Hampshire (Pinkas).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violinist &lt;strong&gt;Saul Bitrán&lt;/strong&gt; has been first violinist with Grammy award-winning Cuarteto Latinoamericano since 1986. A graduate of the Rubin Academy of Music at Tel Aviv University, Bitrán tours worldwide and has recorded extensively with the Cuarteto. As a soloist, he has played with orchestras such as the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Seattle Symphony, Dallas Symphony and National Arts Center Orchestra among many others. The Cuarteto Latinoamericano, recipient of the Mexican government Fine Arts Medal, served as Quartet in Residence at Carnegie Mellon University in Pittsburgh between 1987 and 2008. Currently, the Cuarteto heads the Latin American Academy for String Quartets, in Caracas, Venezuela, under the auspices of the Sistema. Saul Bitrán is Artist in Residence at the College of the Holy Cross, in Worcester, MA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellist &lt;strong&gt;Jan Müller-Szeraws's&lt;/strong&gt; musical journey has taken him over three continents as a soloist, chamber musician and teacher. Recent performances include solo engagements with the New England Philharmonic, the Concord Orchestra, the Boston Landmarks Orchestra, the Moscow Symphony Orchestra, Orquesta Sinfónica de Concepción and Orquesta de la Universidad de Santiago de Chile. His recording of the Allende cello concerto with the Orquesta Sinfónica de Chile has been released by the Chilean Academy of Fine Arts. Other recent recordings include Bernard Hoffer's "Concerto di Camera II" for cello and ensemble written for him and Boston Musica Viva, a CD for Cello, Tabla and Carnatic soprano with works by composer Shirish Korde and Brahms and Chopin sonatas with pianist Adam Golka for Hammond Performing Arts. He is member of contemporary music ensemble Boston Musica Viva, is currently on faculty at the Phillips Academy Andover and has recently been appointed Artist-in-Residence and Chamber Music Coordinator at the College of the Holy Cross in Worcester, MA. He is a grant recipient of the Saul and Naomi Cohen Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following her London debut at Wigmore Hall, Israeli-born pianist &lt;strong&gt;Sally Pinkas&lt;/strong&gt; has been heard as recitalist and chamber musician throughout the USA, Europe, Asia, Russia and Nigeria. She has appeared as soloist with the Boston Pops, Aspen Philharmonia, Jupiter Symphony and the Bulgarian Chamber Orchestra. Summer credits include the festivals at Marlboro, Tanglewood, Aspen, Monadnock, Apple Hill and Rockport, as well as Kfar Blum in Israel, Officina Scotese in Italy and Masters de Pontlevoy in France. Pinkas's extensive solo discography features works by Schumann, Fauré, Debussy, Martinu and Rochberg, released on Naxos, MSR and Centaur.. Pinkas appears regularly with her husband, pianist Evan Hirsch (The Hirsch-Pinkas Piano Duo), and with Ensemble Schumann (with oboist Tom Gallant and violist Steve Larson). Pianist-in-residence at the Hopkins Center at Dartmouth College, she is Professor of Music at Dartmouth's Music Department.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Cosi Quartet</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/cosi-quartet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2016-01-23:/cosi-quartet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/cosi-quartet.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/Cosi200.png" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;January 23 at 8:00pm in the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linda Melsted (Violinist), Laurel Wells (violist), Meg Brennand (cellist), and Curtis …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/cosi-quartet.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/Cosi200.png" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;January 23 at 8:00pm in the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linda Melsted (Violinist), Laurel Wells (violist), Meg Brennand (cellist), and Curtis Foster (oboist) will be performing pieces from the little-known oboe quartet literature featuring pieces by Krommer, Masek, and Mozart, as well as a trio by Eybler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;table width="800" align="center"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center" colspan="2"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Program&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Quartet for oboe, violin viola, cello in F major&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Franz Krommer&lt;/b&gt; (1759-1831)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Quartet for oboe, violin, viola, cello in C major&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pavel Masek&lt;/b&gt; (1761-1826)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="height:10px"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="height:10px"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan="2" class="center"&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;div class="smallheading"&gt;Intermission
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Trio for violin, viola, cello in C major&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Joseph Eybler&lt;/b&gt; (1765-1846)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;TQuartet for oboe, violin, viola, cello in F major, K. 370&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;W.A. Mozart&lt;/b&gt; (1756-1791)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Artiest Bio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curtis Foster&lt;/strong&gt;, Baroque oboe and recorder, has appeared as soloist and member of many outstanding groups, including the Seattle and Pacific Baroque Orchestras, Pacific MusicWorks, American Bach Soloists, Musica Angelica, Mercury Baroque, Bach Society Houston, the Newberry Consort, Victoria Baroque Players, Indianapolis Baroque Orchestra, Chicago Opera Theater, and Baroque Band. Festival Performances include the Vancouver, Chicago, and Bloomington Early Music Festivals, Ottawa International Chamber Music Festival, and the Oregon and Phoenix Bach Festivals. Curtis has performed with small ensembles in concert from San Francisco to Dubai, including appearances with Byron Schenkman and Friends, Seattle Baroque, MusicSources (Berkeley), SacroProfano, as well as his own Seattle-based group, sound | counterpoint. Mr. Foster is also a passionate advocate for music of our own time, and has commissioned and premiered many works by contemporary composers for old instruments.Mr. Foster has recorded for ATMA Classique, Cedille Records, and IU Press. He is a graduate of Indiana University's Early Music Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The passionate artistry of violinist &lt;strong&gt;Linda Melsted&lt;/strong&gt; has won the hearts of audiences across North America, Europe, and Japan. She has appeared as soloist, member, and leader of several outstanding ensembles including Tafelmusik Baroque Orchestra, Freiburg Baroque Orchestra, Portland Baroque Orchestra, Seattle Baroque Orchestra, Pacific Baroque Orchestra, and Pacific Music Works. An active chamber musician, Linda frequently appears on many series including Early Music Vancouver, Gallery Concerts, Skagit Symphony’s Spotlight series, Folia, and Toronto Music Garden. Linda is a co-founder of the new group sound|counterpoint, which recently toured Montana, and Salish Sea Players, a group dedicated to performing in retirement and nursing facilities. She also regularly performs with Marc Destrubé and Friends, Pacific Baroque Festival, and Early Music Underground. Linda performs on a Nicolo Amati violin from 1670.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laurel Wells&lt;/strong&gt; is known for her work on both baroque and modern viola and violin. She has enjoyed an extensive and eclectic musical life, performing in Hong Kong, Norway, Canada, and throughout the United States. For twenty years she played violin with the Lyric Opera of Chicago, between seasons earning Master’s degrees in violin and viola from Indiana University. She studied chamber music at the Banff Centre in Canada and performed extensively under the guidance of the Vermeer Quartet. Laurel was a member of the Northwest Chamber Orchestra, holding the position of principal viola. She is currently a member of the Pacific Northwest Ballet orchestra and performs often with the Seattle Symphony, Seattle Opera, and at the 5th Avenue Theater. In the early music world, Laurel plays with the Seattle Baroque Orchestra, the Pacific MusicWorks, and with her quartet, Opus 20, in the Gallery Concert Series. She has also participated in the Whidbey Island Music Festival, and the EMG's Early Music Fridays. Laurel has recorded with Seattle Baroque, for NPR, and the Wild Boar and Centaur labels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellist &lt;strong&gt;Meg Brennand&lt;/strong&gt; enjoys an eclectic musical life in Seattle. She has been cellist with the critically-acclaimed Onyx Chamber Players since 2001, at Town Hall Seattle and now ensemble-in-residence at First Church Seattle and with whom she has performed throughout the Northwest and on KING-FM. She is also cellist with the Pacific Northwest Ballet Orchestra in Seattle, and she will be part of the second NYC tour in February 2016. Meg serves on the cello faculty at Seattle Pacific University, and she maintains an active cello studio, where she teaches privately and coaches chamber music ensembles. As a member of the period-instrument community in Seattle, Meg performs on baroque cello with the Seattle Baroque Orchestra and Pacific Music Works.She has performed as solo cellist and with small ensembles on Gallery Concerts Series and with the Cosi Quartet. Past seasons have included performances with the Portland Baroque Orchestra and Pacific Baroque Orchestra in Vancouver, BC. Meg is a graduate of the Eastman School of Music.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Rose Ensemble</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/the-rose-ensemble.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2015-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2015-11-21:/the-rose-ensemble.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/the-rose-ensemble.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/TheRoseEnsemble200.png" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;November 21 at 8:00pm in the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rose Ensemble&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Minneapolis–based vocal group returns to our …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/the-rose-ensemble.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/TheRoseEnsemble200.png" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;November 21 at 8:00pm in the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rose Ensemble&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Minneapolis–based vocal group returns to our series with Il Poverello (“the poor one”), a thematic program featuring readings and music about Francis of Assisi ranging from the 12th to the 15th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theroseensemble.com/"&gt;The Rose Ensemble Web Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/Program.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/images/BioNotesTranslationspdf.pdf"&gt;Texts, Translations, and Notes (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Cheifetz and Guggenheim</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/cheifetz-and-guggenheim.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2015-10-24:/cheifetz-and-guggenheim.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/cheifetz-and-guggenheim.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/CheifetzGuggenheim200.png" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;October 24th, 2015 8:00pm at the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamilton Cheifetz, cello and Janet Guggenheim, piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hamiltoncheifetz.com/"&gt;Hamilton Cheifetz Web Site …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/cheifetz-and-guggenheim.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/CheifetzGuggenheim200.png" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;October 24th, 2015 8:00pm at the Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamilton Cheifetz, cello and Janet Guggenheim, piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hamiltoncheifetz.com/"&gt;Hamilton Cheifetz Web Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;table width="800" align="center"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center" colspan="2"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Program&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sonata in G minor, Op. 5, No. 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ludwig van Beethoven&lt;/b&gt; (1770 - 1827)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sonata in C Major, Op. 102, No. 1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Beethoven&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sonata in A Major, Op. 69&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Beethoven&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Artists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hamilton Cheifetz&lt;/strong&gt; has been described in Fanfare Magazine as “unquestionably a magnificent player" for his solo recordings, and he has performed throughout North America and in Europe, Asia, and Australia. A native of Chicago, Cheifetz began playing cello when he was seven and first appeared as soloist with orchestra at the age of eleven. He studied with Janos Starker at Indiana University beginning at the age of 16 and later became the teaching assistant to Tsuyoshi Tsutsumi at the University of Western Ontario. The winner of the Piatigorsky Prize at Tanglewood, he toured the United States and Canada on the Music from Marlboro concert series and performed at the White House for President Carter and the members of Congress. He presented a solo recital in the Sydney Opera House and has often been featured on National Public Radio’s “Performance Today.” His playing was highlighted, together with jazz great Dave Frishberg and vocalist Rebecca Kilgore, on the CBS television special “Gary Larson’s Tales From the Far Side.” In 2001, he performed duos in concert with Janos Starker which were broadcast nationally on NPR, and he appeared with the Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center in New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Cheifetz presented solo recitals and gave master classes in China in the spring of 2010 in Beijing and Tianjin and returned to China for concerts in 2012. He has presented master classes in Korea and taught as Guest Lecturer at Indiana University. He has recorded for Koch, Delos, New World, and Gagliano Recordings and is featured on “Sound of the Five”, chamber music of Chen Yi, with Third Angle Ensemble. In the summer of 2014, he performed at Chamber Music Northwest and in Puebla, Mexico, and this summer he will be featured at Chamber Music Northwest and the Oregon Bach Festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamilton Cheifetz is professor of music at Portland State University and a founding member of the Florestan Trio, which is celebrating its 40th season this year. Together with pianist Janet Guggenheim and violinist Carol Sindell, the Florestan Trio has received international acclaim, including three tours of Japan and concerts in Europe. A dedicated teacher, Professor Cheifetz’s students have gone on to positions in orchestras such as the Boston Symphony and Atlanta Symphony. Hamilton Cheifetz plays a Matteo Goffriller cello made in 1704.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamilton Cheifetz can be heard live in concert in audio recordings and videos at his website at hamiltoncheifetz.com. He is a member of the Subud International Cultural Association, an organization dedicated to promoting original culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Janet Goodman Guggenheim&lt;/strong&gt; began her piano studies with her father when she was five years old and, in her hometown, Spokane, also worked with Margaret Saunders Ott. At the age of ten she was accepted for summer master classes by the legendary piano teacher Rosina Lhevinne, who was her mentor for many years. She made her orchestral debut with the San Francisco Symphony at the age of sixteen. A graduate of the University of California, Berkeley, where she was awarded an Alfred Hertz Fellowship, she received her master's degree at Juilliard, where she was the recipient of the Josef Lhevinne scholarship. She coached under Dame Myra Hess in London and performed concerts throughout Europe. She was a recipient of a Martha Baird Rockefeller Foundation grant. Prior to moving to Portland in 1995 she was on the music faculty at the University of California. She was founding pianist of the Chamber Soloists of San Francisco and has participated in numerous music festivals in the United States and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For over thirty years she collaborated with the celebrated violinist Itzhak Perlman, including concerts in Hong Kong, Taipei, Istanbul and Russia. The Moscow concert encores are included in the DVD, “Perlman Live in Russia”. She has been pianist numerous times on the Johnny Carson Show for Mr. Perlman, Yo Yo Ma, and Nadia Salerno-Sonnenberg. Additionally she has collaborated with violinists Young Uck Kim, David Kim, Dong Suk Kang, Ivry Gitlis, Uto Ughi, Miriam Fried, Pinchas Zukerman, Stuart Canin, hornist Barry Tuckwell, cellists Pierre Fournier and Matt Haimovitz, and has recorded CDs of Rachmaninov and Prokofiev (Naxos) with cellist Michael Grebanier.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Stephen Beus, piano</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/stephen-beus-piano.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2015-09-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2015-09-26:/stephen-beus-piano.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/stephen-beus-piano.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/StephenBeus200.jpg" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;September 26th, 2015 8:00pm and&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;September 27th, 2015 2:00pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Beus, piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://stephenbeus.com/"&gt;Stephen Beus Web …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/stephen-beus-piano.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2015-2016/StephenBeus200.jpg" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;September 26th, 2015 8:00pm and&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;September 27th, 2015 2:00pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Beus, piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://stephenbeus.com/"&gt;Stephen Beus Web Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;table width="800" align="center"&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td align="center" colspan="2"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Program&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;French Suite No.5 in G Major, BWV 816&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;J.S. Bach&lt;/b&gt; (1685-1750)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Chaconne in D Minor from &lt;i&gt;Partita No. 2&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bach-Busoni&lt;/b&gt; (1866-1924)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
     &lt;td colspan="2" class="center"&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;div class="smallheading"&gt;Intermission
        &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Transcendental Etudes S. 139&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Franz Liszt&lt;/b&gt; (1811-1886)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;b&gt;Hungarian Rhapsody No. 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td class="right"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Liszt-Horowitz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Artiest Bio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mesmerizing… explosive… intelligent… he belongs on the world stage” (Salt Lake Tribune). In the space of four months, American pianist Stephen Beus won first prize in the Gina Bachauer International Piano Competition, first place in the Vendome Prize International Competition (Lisbon) and he was awarded the Max I. Allen Fellowship of the American Pianists Association (Indianapolis).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of winning the Juilliard School Concerto Competition Mr. Beus made his Carnegie Hall debut with the Juilliard Orchestra and James DePreist, playing Prokofiev Concerto No. 3. He has also performed as guest soloist with the Gulbenkian Symphony (Lisbon), Oxford Philomusica, the Tivoli Symphony (Copenhagen), the Tbilisi National Opera Orchestra, the Northwest Sinfonietta (Seattle), the Royal Philharmonic of Morocco (Casablanca), the Vaasa Symphony Orchestra (Finland) as well as with the Hamburg, Indianapolis, Nashville, Santa Fe, Utah, Fort Worth, Tucson, Yakima, Bellevue, Salt Lake, Eastern Sierra, Corvallis, Jacksonville, Texarkana and Walla Walla Symphonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equally active as a soloist, Mr. Beus has performed at Wigmore Hall, the Salle Gaveau and Salle Cortot (Paris), Merkin Hall, the Shanghai Oriental Arts Center, the Central Conservatory (Beijing), Teatro San Carlo (Naples), Carnegie Hall (Weill Recital Hall), the Queluz Palace (Lisbon) and has performed for the Dame Myra Hess and Fazioli Salon series (Chicago), the International Keyboard Institute and Festival (New York City), and has given recitals across the United States as well as in Kazakhstan, Russia, Finland, Denmark, Switzerland, Germany, Georgia, China, France, Italy, Portugal, the Czech Republic, and Morocco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born and raised on a farm in eastern Washington, Mr. Beus began lessons at age 5 and made his orchestral debut four years later. He went on to win numerous national and international competitions throughout his youth, capturing the attention of both audiences and critics. Commenting on Mr. Beus’ competition success, Fanfare magazine writes: “In some ways Beus doesn’t fit the mold of the typical competition winner. His playing is strikingly original and, despite his youth, he has an interpretive voice all his own… Above all, his playing is so natural as to seem effortless and the sound he produces has extraordinary richness and depth, not quite like anyone else’s.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Beus holds degrees from Whitman College, The Juilliard School, and Stony Brook University, where his teachers have included Leonard Richter, Robert McDonald, Gilbert Kalish and Christina Dahl. He has recorded on the Endeavor Classics and Harmonia Mundi labels. Stephen Beus is a Steinway Artist and currently teaches at the University of Oklahoma.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>