<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Camerata Musica - 2017-2018</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/feeds/2017-2018.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://cameratamusica.com/</id><updated>2018-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Young Artists of Distinction</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/young-artists-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2018-05-06:/young-artists-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/young-artists-2018.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2017-2018/YoungArtists400.jpg" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;May 6th, 2018 2:00 pm at &lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gallery at the Richland Public Library &lt;br&gt;
955 Northgate Dr, Richland, WA 99352 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/young-artists-2018.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2017-2018/YoungArtists400.jpg" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;May 6th, 2018 2:00 pm at &lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gallery at the Richland Public Library &lt;br&gt;
955 Northgate Dr, Richland, WA 99352 (&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Richland+Public+Library/@46.279784,-119.278918,15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0xf2400b4831762b5a!8m2!3d46.279784!4d-119.278918"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kory Carterby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ruggero Leoncavallo: Mattinata&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Holly Shaw&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;David Popper: Hungarian Rhapsody, Op. 68&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kristen Nakamura&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Frédéric Chopin: Nocturne in C-sharp minor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nathan Hu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ludwig van Beethoven: Sonata Op. 10, No. 1 in C minor, 1st movement&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Karissa Nakamura&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Carl Kölling: Fluttering Leaves&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Claudia Wells&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J. S. Bach: Suite No. 1 in G Major, Prelude&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alice Xu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A. Babajanian: Humoresque&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Emilie Cooper&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;G. Antheil: Valentine Waltzes #VII-IX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Daniel Li&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H. Eccles: Sonata No. 11 in G minor - Largo, Allegro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jessica Chen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Friedrich Kuhlau: Sonatina in C, Op. 55 No. 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Le-Yi Wang&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sergei Rachmaninoff: Polka&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Noni Mosher&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Henryk Wieniawski: Romance Concerto No. 2 in D minor, Op. 22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sofia Marina&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Edvard Grieg: Piano Sonata in E minor, Op. 7, I. Allegro Moderato&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Audrey Xu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W. A. Mozart: Fantasie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ourania Glezakou-Elbert&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;V. Kalinnikov: Elégie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year, Camerata celebrates the end of the season with a tribute to local music students.  About 15-20 participants are selected from a group nominated by their teachers on the basis of performance at adjudications and competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about this event, please send an email to &lt;a href="mailto:youngartists@cameratamusica.com"&gt;youngartists@cameratamusica.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Byron Schenkman &amp; Friends</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/byron-schenkman-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2018-04-21:/byron-schenkman-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;April 21st, 2018 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joshua Romatowski, flute &lt;br&gt;
Debra Nagy, oboe &lt;br&gt;
Anna Marsh, bassoon &lt;br&gt;
Ingrid Matthews …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;April 21st, 2018 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joshua Romatowski, flute &lt;br&gt;
Debra Nagy, oboe &lt;br&gt;
Anna Marsh, bassoon &lt;br&gt;
Ingrid Matthews, violin &lt;br&gt;
Nathan Whittaker, cello &lt;br&gt;
Byron Schenkman, harpsichord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://byronschenkman.com/series/"&gt;Byron Schenkman website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Trio-sonata in D, RV 84&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Oboe Sonata in G Minor, RV 28&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joseph Bodin de Boismortier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Trio-sonata in G Major, op. 37, no. 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Joseph Bodin de Boismortier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Concerto in E Minor, op. 37, no. 6,&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intermission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Anna Bon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Harpsichord Sonata in C, op. 2, no. 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Giuseppe Brescianello&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Trio-sonata in C Minor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Johann Ernst Galliard&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Bassoon Sonata no. 2 in G&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Concerto in D "Il Gardelino"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BYRON SCHENKMAN has recorded more than thirty CDs of 17th- and 18th-century repertoire, including recordings on historical instruments from the National Music Museum, Vermillion, and the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. A recipient of the Erwin Bodky Award from the Cambridge Society for Early Music “for outstanding achievement in the field of early music,” he was voted “Best Classical Instrumentalist” by the readers of Seattle Weekly in 2006, and his piano playing has been described in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; as “sparkling,” “elegant,” and “insightful.” He has been a featured guest with the Chameleon Arts Ensemble of Boston, the Daedalus Quartet, the Northwest Sinfonietta, Pacific Baroque Orchestra, Philharmonia Northwest, and the Portland Baroque Orchestra. He was also founding co-director of the Seattle Baroque Orchestra with violinist Ingrid Matthews. In 2013 he launched “Byron Schenkman &amp;amp; Friends,” a Baroque and Classical chamber music series at Benaroya Hall in Seattle. Recently he has been studying Klezmer music with Shawn Weaver and has begun collaborating on performances of Russian Jewish art music with violinist Steven Greenman. Schenkman is a graduate of the New England Conservatory and received his master’s degree with honors in performance from the Indiana University School of Music. He currently teaches at Seattle University and Cornish College of the Arts. In 2012 he also served as guest lecturer in harpsichord and fortepiano at the Indiana University Jacobs School of Music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes on the Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Byron Schenkman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Antonio Vivaldi, most chamber music featured pairs or groups of
like instruments such as trio sonatas for two violins and continuo or string
concertos or (earlier) consorts for recorders or viols. In the early 18th
century Vivaldi popularized sonatas and concertos for diverse
combinations of instruments including many chamber concertos for flute,
oboe, violin, bassoon, and continuo. Besides being a celebrated violinist
and a prolific opera composer, Vivaldi presided over the &lt;em&gt;Ospedale della
Pieta&lt;/em&gt;, a famous Venetian music school and home for girls. Some of the
young musicians in residence there were orphans; others came from
wealthy families willing to pay for their daughters to have such a great
musical education. The virtuosity of the music Vivaldi composed for these
students indicates that there must have been many phenomenally talented
young women and girls at the &lt;em&gt;Ospedale&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Bodin de Boismortier was one of the first composers to earn a
living by selling music to the general public, neither relying on a church,
court, or theater for employment, nor on aristocratic patronage. Therefore
he had to be up on the latest fashions and to present works with broad
popular appeal. His opus 37 contains five trio sonatas which
he indicates may be performed by flute and viol, oboe and bassoon, or
violin and cello (always with continuo accompaniment), retaining the
traditional preference for pairing like instruments when possible. These five
trios are then followed by a chamber concerto with the mixed
instrumentation most typical of Vivaldi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Bon was one of the paying students at the &lt;em&gt;Ospedale della Pieta&lt;/em&gt;
beginning at the age of four. While still a teenager she was hired as a
professional singer at the Brandenburg court in Bayreuth. She published
three volumes of instrumental music by the time she was nineteen before
marrying and drifting into obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The violinist Giuseppe Antonio Brescianello was another of the many
Italian musicians employed at German courts during the Baroque era.
European music was becoming increasingly international in flavor and his
C Minor trio sonata incorporates French dotted rhythms in the first
movement, Italian virtuosity in the second, and German &lt;em&gt;empfindsamkeit&lt;/em&gt; (a
kind of expressive sensitivity) in the third. Meanwhile Johann Ernst Galliard
was a German musician who settled in England where he became the
principal oboist in George Friderick Handel’s opera orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Photo Credit: Will Austin&lt;/h5&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Rose City Trio</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/rose-city-trio.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2018-03-24:/rose-city-trio.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/rose-city-trio.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2017-2018/rose-city-trio-400.jpg" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;March 24th, 2018 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Kwak, violin &lt;br&gt;
Nancy Ives, cello &lt;br&gt;
Susan Chan, piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Piano …&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/rose-city-trio.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2017-2018/rose-city-trio-400.jpg" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;March 24th, 2018 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Kwak, violin &lt;br&gt;
Nancy Ives, cello &lt;br&gt;
Susan Chan, piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Piano Trio No. 39 in G Major, Hob. XV/25 "Gypsy"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Franz Joseph Haydn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Piano Trio in G Minor, Op. 17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Clara Schumann&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intermission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Trio No. 2 in C Major for Piano, Violin and Cello, Op. 87&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Johannes Brahms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Rose City Trio&lt;/strong&gt; is a recently founded piano trio in Portland. Its members consist
of violinist Sarah Kwak, cellist Nancy Ives, and pianist Susan Chan, who have
performed nationally and internationally as soloists and chamber musicians in
various groups, and whose performances have received critical acclaim. Sarah Kwak
and Nancy Ives are currently the Concertmaster and Principal Cello of the Oregon
Symphony, and Susan Chan serves as Associate Professor of Music and Piano Area
Coordinator at Portland State University. The Trio has been performing in various
venues in Portland, including Portland State University and on the Classical Up Close
Series of the Oregon Symphony.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Aeolus Quartet</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/aeolus-quartet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2018-02-24:/aeolus-quartet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;February 24th, 2018 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicholas Tavani violin &lt;br&gt;
Rachel Shapiro, violin &lt;br&gt;
Caitlyn Lynch, viola &lt;br&gt;
Alan Richardson …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;February 24th, 2018 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicholas Tavani violin &lt;br&gt;
Rachel Shapiro, violin &lt;br&gt;
Caitlyn Lynch, viola &lt;br&gt;
Alan Richardson, cello&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://aeolusquartet.com/"&gt;Aeolus Quartet website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F. Joseph Haydn (1732-1809):&lt;/strong&gt; String Quartet in F, Op. 74 no. 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F. Mendelssohn (1809-1847):&lt;/strong&gt; String Quartet No. 2 in A minor, Op. 13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L.V. Beethoven (1770-1827):&lt;/strong&gt; String Quartet in C# minor, Op. 131&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praised by the Baltimore Sun for combining “smoothly meshed technique with a sense of spontaneity and discovery,” the Aeolus Quartet is committed to presenting time-seasoned masterworks and new cutting-edge works to widely diverse audiences with equal freshness, dedication, and fervor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aeolus Quartet was formed in 2008 at the Cleveland Institute of Music. Since its inception, the all-American quartet has been awarded prizes at nearly every major competition in the United States and performed across the globe with showings "worthy of a major-league quartet" (Scott Cantrell, Dallas Morning News). Luke Quinton of the Austin American Statesman writes, “The Aeolus Quartet is a powerful and thoughtful group of young musicians who are plotting an ascending course…this vibrant group shows great promise.” They were the 2013-2015 Graduate Resident String Quartet at the Juilliard School, and they currently make their home in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aeolus Quartet are Grand Prizewinners of the 2011 Plowman Chamber Music Competition and 2011 Chamber Music Yellow Springs Competition. They were awarded First Prize at the 2009 Coleman International Chamber Ensemble Competition, a Silver Medal at the 2011 Fischoff International Chamber Music Competition, and a Bronze Medal at the 2010 International Chamber Music Ensemble Competition in New England. The 16th Annual Austin Critics' Table named the Aeolus Quartet their 2010-2011 "Best Ensemble." The Aeolus Quartet has released two critically acclaimed albums of classical and contemporary works through the Longhorn/Naxos label which are available on iTunes, Amazon, and major retailers worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quartet has performed across North America, Europe, and Asia in venues such as Alice Tully Hall at Lincoln Center, Weill Recital Hall at Carnegie Hall, Reinberger Recital Hall at Severance Hall, Merkin Hall, The Library of Congress, Renwick Gallery, St. Martin-in-the-Fields, and the Shanghai Oriental Arts Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dedicated to bringing music into the community, the Aeolus Quartet has been widely recognized for their highly innovative and engaging outreach programs. For the 2015-2016 season, the Quartet was the recipient of a CMA Residency Partnership Grant. Named the 2015-2016 Guarneri Quartet Residency in recognition of Aeolus' artistic achievement, the project involved extensive outreach and performance at Duke Ellington School for the Arts, the Sitar Arts Center, and George Washington University. The Fischoff National Chamber Music Association awarded the Aeolus their 2013 Educator Award in acknowledgment of the positive impact their educational efforts have had in diverse communities. Additionally, they were awarded the 2012 Lad Prize which culminated in large-scale community engagement work, performing in the Stanford area, and a masterclass residency at Stanford University. The Aeolus Quartet has also served as teaching faculty at Stanford University's Education Program for Gifted Youth (EPGY), the Austin Chamber Music Workshop, and Da Camera of Houston's Music Encounters Program. Working in collaboration with the University of Texas through the Rural Chamber Music Outreach Initiative, the Quartet has presented educational programs and performances in communities throughout the state of Texas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aeolus Quartet has studied extensively with the Miró, Guarneri, and Juilliard Quartets. Other mentors include artists such as William Preucil, Peter Salaff, Donald Weilerstein, Itzhak Perlman, Gerhard Schulz, and Mark Steinberg. Members of the Quartet hold degrees from the Peabody Conservatory, the Cleveland Institute of Music, and the University of Texas at Austin, where they served as the first Graduate String Quartet-in-Residence.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Clancy Newman with Natalie Zhu</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/clancy-newman-with-natalie-zhu.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2018-01-27:/clancy-newman-with-natalie-zhu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;January 27th, 2018 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clancy Newman, cello &lt;br&gt;
Natalie Zhu, piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.clancynewman.com/"&gt;Clancy Newman website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beethoven …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;January 27th, 2018 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clancy Newman, cello &lt;br&gt;
Natalie Zhu, piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.clancynewman.com/"&gt;Clancy Newman website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beethoven:&lt;/strong&gt; Variations on a Theme from the Magic Flute, Wo O 46, "Bei Mannern,
welche Liebe fuhlen" (1801)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schumann:&lt;/strong&gt; Five Pieces in Folk Style, Op. 102 I: Mit Humor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newman:&lt;/strong&gt; Pop-Unpopped: Inspired by the Billboard Charts &lt;br&gt;
I: Meghan Trainor: &lt;em&gt;All About That Bass&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
II: Fetty Wap: &lt;em&gt;Trap Queen&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
III: Mark Ronson: &lt;em&gt;Uptown Funk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INTERMISSION&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prokoviev:&lt;/strong&gt; Sonata for Cello and Piano, Op. 119&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newman:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;From Method to Madness (2008)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Artists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellist &lt;strong&gt;Clancy Newman&lt;/strong&gt;, first prize winner of the prestigious Walter W. Naumburg
International Competition and recipient of an Avery Fisher Career Grant, has had the
unusual career of a performer/composer. From Albany, NY, he began playing cello at
the age of six, and at twelve he received his first significant public recognition when he
won a Gold Medal at the Dandenong Youth Festival in Australia, competing against
contestants twice his age. In the years that followed, he won numerous other
competitions, including the Juilliard School Cello Competition, the National Federation
of Music Clubs competition, and the Astral Artists National Auditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has performed as soloist throughout the United States, as well as in Europe, Asia,
Canada, and Australia. He can often be heard on NPR’s “Performance Today” and has
been featured on A&amp;amp;E’s “Breakfast With the Arts”. A sought after chamber musician, he
is a member of the Chicago Chamber Musicians, and a former member of Chamber
Music Society Two of Lincoln Center. He has also toured as a member of “Musicians
from Marlboro”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He developed an interest in composition at an early age, writing his first piece at seven, a
piece for solo cello. Since then, he has greatly expanded the cello repertoire: he
premiered his &lt;em&gt;Four Pieces for Solo Cello&lt;/em&gt; at the Violoncello Society in New York, his
&lt;em&gt;Sonata for Cello and Piano&lt;/em&gt; in New York's Weill Hall, and his &lt;em&gt;Four Seasons&lt;/em&gt; for cello and
string orchestra with Symphony in C in Philadelphia. He has also written numerous
chamber music works, including two string quartets, a clarinet trio, and a piano quintet.
He has been a featured composer on the Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center’s
“Double Exposure” series and the Chicago Chamber Musicians’ “Freshly Scored” series,
and has received commissions from Astral Artists, the Barnett Foundation, the Carpe
Diem String Quartet, and the Silo Collective, among others. His piano trio, &lt;em&gt;Juxt-Opposition&lt;/em&gt;,
is available on Bridge Records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Newman is a graduate of the five-year exchange program between Juilliard and
Columbia University, receiving a M.M. from Juilliard and a B.A. in English from
Columbia. His teachers have included David Gibson, Joel Krosnick and Harvey Shapiro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipient of a 2006 Musical Fund Society Career Advancement Award, the 2003 Avery Fisher Career Grant and the 2003 Andrew Wolf Memorial Chamber Music Award, pianist &lt;strong&gt;Natalie Zhu&lt;/strong&gt; is a winner of Astral Artistic Services' 1998 National Auditions. The Philadelphia Inquirer heralded Astral’s presentation of Ms. Zhu in recital as a display of "emotional and pianistic pyrotechnics"; selections from the recital were later broadcast on National Public Radio’s "Performance Today."  Natalie Zhu began her piano studies with Xiao-Cheng Liu at the age of six in her native China and made her first public appearance at age nine in Beijing. At eleven she emigrated with her family to Los Angeles, and by fifteen was enrolled at the Curtis Institute, where she received the Rachmaninoff Award and studied with Gary Graffman. She received a Master of Music degree from the Yale School of Music, where she studied with Claude Frank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Photo Credit: Lisa-Marie Mazzucco&lt;/h5&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>sound|counterpoint</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/soundcounterpoint.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2017-11-18:/soundcounterpoint.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;November 18th, 2017 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miyo Aoki, recorder &lt;br&gt;
Linda Melsted, violin &lt;br&gt;
Curtis Foster, oboe &lt;br&gt;
Jonathan Oddie …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;November 18th, 2017 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miyo Aoki, recorder &lt;br&gt;
Linda Melsted, violin &lt;br&gt;
Curtis Foster, oboe &lt;br&gt;
Jonathan Oddie, harpsichord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://soundcounterpoint.org/"&gt;sound|counterpoint website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program: Sonate auf Concertenart&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johann Friedrich Fasch, Sonata in B-flat Major &lt;br&gt;
Johann Sebastian Bach, Sonata for Violin and Harpsichord no. 6 in G Major &lt;br&gt;
Antonio Vivaldi, Concerto in A minor &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Intermission&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Johann Sebastian Bach, Trio Sonata BWV 1039 in B-flat major &lt;br&gt;
Georg Philipp Telemann, Concerto in A minor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Established in 2014, &lt;strong&gt;sound|counterpoint&lt;/strong&gt; is charming audiences throughout the Pacific
Northwest and beyond with its performances of music from the late Renaissance,
Baroque, and 21st century. Based in Seattle, this new ensemble has quickly gained a
reputation for performances of expressive generosity, spontaneity, vivacity, and
virtuosity. &lt;strong&gt;sound|counterpoint’s&lt;/strong&gt; members play with many of North America’s top
ensembles, including Seattle Baroque Orchestra, Portland Baroque Orchestra, American
Bach Soloists, Pacific Music Works, and Pacific Baroque Orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This program is supported in part by a grant from &lt;a href="http://www.arts.wa.gov/"&gt;ArtsWa&lt;/a&gt; (the &lt;a href="http://www.arts.wa.gov/"&gt;Washington State Arts Commission&lt;/a&gt;) and the &lt;a href="https://www.arts.gov/"&gt;National Endowment for the Arts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=" " src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/nea-lockup-A-small.jpg" width="500px"&gt;
&lt;img alt=" " src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/TextOnlyAndFullName-HiRes-small.jpg" width="300px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>New York Brass Arts Trio</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/new-york-brass-arts-trio.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2017-10-28:/new-york-brass-arts-trio.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;October 28th, 2017 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Burgstaller, trumpet &lt;br&gt;
David Jolley, french horn &lt;br&gt;
Haim Avitsur, trombone  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dispeker.com/artist.php?id=nybrassarts"&gt;New …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;October 28th, 2017 8:00 pm at Battelle Auditorium&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Burgstaller, trumpet &lt;br&gt;
David Jolley, french horn &lt;br&gt;
Haim Avitsur, trombone  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dispeker.com/artist.php?id=nybrassarts"&gt;New York Brass Arts Trio website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concert is made possible in part by a grant from Battelle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Johann Sebastian Bach (arr. Jolley)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Three Sinfonias &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ludwig van Beethoven (arr. Avitsur)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Trio in C Major, Op. 87&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Richard Strauss (arr. Jolley)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Till Eulenspiegel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intermission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Astor Piazzola (arr. Burgstaller)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Adios Nonino&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Igor Stravinsky (arr. Jolley)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt; Selection from Pulcinella Suite&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bela Bartok&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Romanian Folk Dances &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Stick Dance&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Sash Dance&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;In One Spot&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Dance from Bucsum&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Romanian Polka&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fast Dance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chick Corea (b.1941) (Arr. Burgstaller)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Three Children’s Songs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Astor Piazzola (arr. Burgstaller)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;Libertango&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three world-class virtuoso soloists have come together to revolutionize the brass trio, and are being hailed as the first brass group ever to play with the sensitivity and musicality of a string quartet. Trumpeter &lt;strong&gt;Joe Burgstaller&lt;/strong&gt; (formerly of Canadian Brass), french hornist &lt;strong&gt;David Jolley&lt;/strong&gt; (founding member of Orpheus Chamber Orchestra) and trombonist &lt;strong&gt;Haim Avitsur&lt;/strong&gt; (Symphony Magazine Emerging Artist) have forged together Classical, Light Classical and Classical/Jazz masterworks of all eras and adapted them for this fantastic and versatile instrumentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The members of the New York Brass Arts Trio bring some serious experience to the table. Burgstaller is a former featured trumpeter and arranger with the legendary Canadian Brass, has performed in front of more than 40 orchestras, and has recording credentials that include solo CDs, three Top-10 Billboard hits, and a Top-50 JazzRadio hit. Jolley is a pre-eminent horn soloist of his generation, performing as a soloist with major orchestras, collaborating with major string quartets (Guarnieri, Orion and American), and is a founding member of the Grammy-winning Orpheus Chamber Orchestra. Avitsur is the only trombonist named a 2005 and 2007 Emerging Artist by &lt;em&gt;Symphony Magazine&lt;/em&gt; and has premiered over 80 compositions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to their individual performance accomplishments, the members of the Trio all maintain teaching posts at major American musical institutions (Peabody Institute, Manhattan School, Mannes, North Carolina School for the Arts, Queens College and Westchester University).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This concert is made possible in part by a grant from Battelle.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Yael Weiss</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/yael-weiss.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2017-09-23:/yael-weiss.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;September 23rd, 2017 8:00 pm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;This concert will be held at Kennewick First United Methodist Church, 2 S. Dayton …&lt;/h4&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;September 23rd, 2017 8:00 pm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;This concert will be held at Kennewick First United Methodist Church, 2 S. Dayton Street, Kennewick&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yael Weiss, Piano&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.yaelweiss.com/"&gt;Yael Weiss web site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beethoven: Sonata no. 24 in F sharp major, Op. 78 &lt;br&gt;
Schumann: Humoreske, Op. 20  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Intermission&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Chopin: Ballade in g minor, Op. 23 &lt;br&gt;
Paul Chihara: Rag 109  &lt;br&gt;
Beethoven: Sonata no. 30 in E major, Op. 109&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musician&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acclaimed as a pianist of "consummate artistry" (&lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;Yael Weiss&lt;/strong&gt; has performed across the United States, Europe, Japan, Korea and South America at such venues as the Kennedy Center, Carnegie Hall, Alice Tully Hall and London's Wigmore Hall. Her New York recital debut, presented by the Metropolitan Museum, was acclaimed by the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; as "remarkably powerful and intense... fine technique and musicianship in the service of an arresting array of music."&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>