<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Camerata Musica - 2018-2019</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/feeds/2018-2019.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://cameratamusica.com/</id><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Young Artists of Distinction</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/young-artists-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2019-05-05:/young-artists-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/young-artists-2019.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2018-2019/YoungArtists400.jpg" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;May 5th, 2019 2:00 pm at &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Kennewick+First+Presbyterian+Church"&gt;Kennewick First Presbyterian Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year, Camerata celebrates the end …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/young-artists-2019.html"&gt;&lt;img _="," alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2018-2019/YoungArtists400.jpg" width="200px"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;May 5th, 2019 2:00 pm at &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Kennewick+First+Presbyterian+Church"&gt;Kennewick First Presbyterian Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year, Camerata celebrates the end of the season with a tribute to local music students.  About 15-20 participants are selected from a group nominated by their teachers on the basis of performance at adjudications and competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about this event, please send an email to &lt;a href="mailto:youngartists@cameratamusica.com"&gt;youngartists@cameratamusica.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
**Submit an application**

Teachers are invited to nominate their outstanding students for participation in the concert.

All applications are due by April 13th, 2019 and [can be submited online](https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdD9urlulZphMZ1c4eUhopvWvWLDDBsf2clzJklpdpMbzmhrg/viewform?usp=sf_link). Please [send us an email](mailto:youngartists@cameratamusica.com) if you have any questions.
--&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Paul O’Dette and Ronn McFarlane</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/paul-odette-and-ronn-mcfarlane.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2019-04-27:/paul-odette-and-ronn-mcfarlane.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;April 27, 2019 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Kennewick+First+Presbyterian+Church"&gt;Kennewick First Presbyterian Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul O’Dette &lt;br&gt;
Ronn McFarlane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esm.rochester.edu/faculty/odette_paul/"&gt;Paul O’Dette website …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;April 27, 2019 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Kennewick+First+Presbyterian+Church"&gt;Kennewick First Presbyterian Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul O’Dette &lt;br&gt;
Ronn McFarlane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esm.rochester.edu/faculty/odette_paul/"&gt;Paul O’Dette website&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.ronnmcfarlane.com/"&gt;Ronn McFarlane website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Two Lutes: Virtuoso Duets from Italy and England&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saltarello &amp;amp; Piva                          Joanambrosio Dalza (pub. 1508) &lt;br&gt;
Contrapunto Primo                     Vincenzo Galilei (c. 1520-1591) &lt;br&gt;
Canzona Prima à doi liutti unisoni          Claudio Merulo/ arr. Giovanni Antonio Terzi (pub. 1593) &lt;br&gt;
Passacaglia                                    Alessandro Piccinini   (1566-1638) &lt;br&gt;
Toccata à dui Liuti                        Alessandro Piccinini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intermission&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dreweries accordes        Anonymous (c.1600)   &lt;br&gt;
Galliard after Laveche                    Anonymous &lt;br&gt;
De la Tromba Pavin                         Anonymous &lt;br&gt;
The Earl of Essex Galliard            John Dowland  (1563-1626) &lt;br&gt;
A Fancy                                            John Danyel (1564-after 1625) &lt;br&gt;
Fantasie #7                                       John Dowland  &lt;br&gt;
Chi Passa                                          John Johnson (? - 1594) &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2018-2019/lute-essay.pdf"&gt;Program Notes (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul O'Dette,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“…should
I come to meet Saint Peter at the pearly gates, I hope he will say, ‘Welcome,
good and faithful servant! By the way, be sure to hear Paul O’Dette—he’s
leading the angel band.’”&lt;/em&gt; Early Music America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul O'Dette has been described as “the clearest case of genius ever to touch his
instrument.” (Toronto Globe and Mail) One of the most influential figures in his field, O'Dette has
helped define the technical and stylistic standards to which
twenty-first-century performers of early music aspire. In doing so, he helped
infuse the performance practice movement with a perfect combination of
historical awareness, idiomatic accuracy, and ambitious self-expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul O'Dette has made more than 140 recordings, winning two Grammys, seven
Grammy nominations and numerous other international record awards. “The
Complete Lute Music of John Dowland” (a 5-CD set for harmonia mundi usa), was
awarded the prestigious &lt;em&gt;Diapason D'or de
l'année&lt;/em&gt;, while “The Royal Lewters” received the &lt;em&gt;Diapason D’or&lt;/em&gt;, a &lt;em&gt;Choc du
Monde de la Musique&lt;/em&gt;, a 5-star rating in &lt;em&gt;BBC
Music Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, 5-star rating in &lt;em&gt;Goldberg&lt;/em&gt;
and a perfect score of 10 from ClassicsToday.com. “The Bachelar’s Delight: Lute
Music of Daniel Bacheler” was nominated for a GRAMMY in 2006 as “Best Solo
Instrumental Recording.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. O'Dette is also active conducting Baroque operas. His recent recording
of Charpentier’s &lt;em&gt;La Descente d’Orphée aux
Enfers&lt;/em&gt; with the Boston Early Music Festival Chamber Ensemble won a GRAMMY
for “Best Opera Recording of 2014,” as well as an Echo Klassik Award in the
same category. In 1997 he began a collaboration with Stephen Stubbs,
co-directing performances of Baroque operas, beginning with Luigi Rossi's &lt;em&gt;L'Orfeo&lt;/em&gt; at Tanglewood, the Boston Early
Music Festival (BEMF) and the Drottningholm Court Theatre in Sweden. Since 1999
they have co-directed performances of Cavalli's &lt;em&gt;Ercole Amante&lt;/em&gt; at the Boston Early Music Festival, Tanglewood, and
the Utrecht Early Music Festival, Provenzale's &lt;em&gt;La Stellidaura Vendicata&lt;/em&gt; at the Vadstena Academy in Sweden,
Monteverdi's &lt;em&gt;Orfeo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;L'Incoronazione di Poppea&lt;/em&gt; for Festival
Vancouver, Lully's &lt;em&gt;Thésée&lt;/em&gt;, Conradi’s &lt;em&gt;Ariadne&lt;/em&gt; (Hamburg, 1691) Mattheson’s &lt;em&gt;Boris Goudenow&lt;/em&gt;, Lully’s &lt;em&gt;Psyché&lt;/em&gt;, Monteverdi’s &lt;em&gt;Poppea&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ulisse&lt;/em&gt;, Handel’s &lt;em&gt;Acis and
Galatea&lt;/em&gt;, Steffani’s &lt;em&gt;Niobe _andHandel’s&lt;/em&gt; Almira &lt;em&gt;for the Boston Early Music Festival. Their recording of _Ariadne&lt;/em&gt; was nominated for a GRAMMY as
“Best Opera Recording of 2005,” &lt;em&gt;Thésée&lt;/em&gt;  in 2007 and &lt;em&gt;Psyché&lt;/em&gt; in 2008. Their most recent opera recording, &lt;em&gt;Niobe&lt;/em&gt;, was awarded a &lt;em&gt;Diapason D’or de l’année&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Echo Klassik
Award&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Jahrespreis der
Deutschenschallplattenkritik&lt;/em&gt;, and was nominated for this year’s Grammys.
Paul O'Dette has guest directed numerous Baroque orchestras and opera
productions on both sides of the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to his activities as a performer, Paul O'Dette is an avid
researcher, having worked extensively on the performance and sources of
seventeenth-century Italian and English solo song, continuo practices and lute
music. He has published numerous articles on issues of historical performance
practice and co-authored the Dowland entry in the &lt;em&gt;New Grove Dictionary of Music and Musicians&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul O'Dette is Professor of Lute and Director of Early Music at the
Eastman School of Music and Artistic Director of the Boston Early Music
Festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ronn McFarlane&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRAMMY­nominated
lutenist, Ronn McFarlane strives to bring the lute ­ the most popular
instrument of the Renaissance ­ into today’s musical mainstream and make it
accessible to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born in West Virginia,
Ronn grew up in Maryland. At thirteen, upon hearing “Wipeout” by the Surfaris,
he fell madly in love with music and taught himself to play on a “cranky
sixteen­dollar steel string guitar.” Ronn kept at it, playing blues and rock
music on the electric guitar while studying classical guitar.  He graduated with honors from Shenandoah
Conservatory and continued guitar studies at Peabody Conservatory before
turning his full attention and energy to the lute in 1978.  The next year, Mr. McFarlane began to perform
solo recitals on the lute and became a member of the Baltimore Consort. Since
then, he has toured throughout the United States, Canada and Europe with the
Baltimore Consort and as a soloist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McFarlane was a faculty
member of the Peabody Conservatory from 1984 to 1995, teaching lute and
lute-related subjects.  In 1996, Mr.
McFarlane was awarded an honorary Doctorate of Music from Shenandoah
Conservatory for his achievements in bringing the lute and its music to the
world.  He has over 35 recordings on the
Dorian/Sono Luminus label, including solo albums, lute duets, flute &amp;amp; lute
duets, lute songs, the complete lute music of Vivaldi, a collection of
Elizabethan lute music and poetry, and recordings with the Baltimore Consort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ronn has composed new
music for the lute, building on the tradition of the lutenist/composers of past
centuries.  His original compositions are
the focus of his solo CD, &lt;em&gt;Indigo Road&lt;/em&gt;,
which received a GRAMMY Award Nomination for Best Classical Crossover Album of
2009.  In 2010 Ronn founded Ayreheart, an
ensemble brought together to perform new compositions as well as early music.
Ayreheart’s first CD release, &lt;em&gt;One Morning&lt;/em&gt;,
consists of all­original music by Ronn McFarlane.  Ayreheart’s 2016 release, &lt;em&gt;Barley Moon&lt;/em&gt;, blends folk music and art
music from Renaissance and Medieval England, Scotland and Wales.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Aristeia Trio</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/aristeia-trio.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2019-03-23:/aristeia-trio.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;March 23, 2019 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annie Jacobs-Perkins, cello &lt;br&gt;
Vijay Venkatesh, piano  &lt;br&gt;
Micah …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;March 23, 2019 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annie Jacobs-Perkins, cello &lt;br&gt;
Vijay Venkatesh, piano  &lt;br&gt;
Micah Wright, clarinet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://classicsaliveartists.org/artists/AristeiaTrio/home.html"&gt;Aristeia Trio website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kegelstatt Trio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;W.A. Mozart&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1756-1791&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Andante&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Menuetto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Allegretto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Trio in Bb, Op. 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ludwig van Beethoven&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1929-2010&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Allegro con brio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adagio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tema con variazioni&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[INTERMISSION]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fantasy Trio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Robert Muczynski&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Allegro energico&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Andante con espressione&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Allegro deciso&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Eight Pieces&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Max Bruch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1832-1920&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;III. Andante con moto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IV. Allegro agitato&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;V. Andante "Rumänische Melodie"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VII. Allegro vivace&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Golliwog's Cakewalk&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Claude Debussy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1862-1918&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aristeia Trio&lt;/strong&gt; is a newly-formed trio based in Los Angeles. Annie Jacobs-Perkins (cello), Vijay Venkatesh (piano), and Micah Wright (clarinet) met as students at the USC Thornton School of Music. While Aristeia Trio has only existed since 2016, the trio has already given dozens of performances in Los Angeles, Seattle, and Washington state. As winners of the 2016 Frances Walton Competition, the trio performed a live, nationally-broadcast concert on KING FM 98.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vijay Venkatesh&lt;/strong&gt;, pianist, a native of Orange County, California, has been hailed in concert review for his “sublime phrasing, tremendous and powerful virtuosity, beautiful lyricism, and mature and sensitive interpretation” in performances “equaling that of Radu Lupu, Itzhak Perlman, and Andres Segovia.” At age 14, he made his orchestral debut with the South Coast Symphony. In addition, he has performed with the Symphony Orchestras of Seattle, Vienna, Roanoke, USC Thornton, Eastern Connecticut, YMF Debut, UCI, Pasadena, Rio Hondo, Transylvania, and the Brevard Music Center. He has collaborated with such celebrated conductors as Ludovic Morlot, David Lockington, David Stewart Wiley, Toshiyuki Shimada, Ken Lam, Robert Lehrbaumer, Kimo Furumoto, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His 2016-17 season contains a performance with USC Thornton Symphony and recitals at the McCallum Theatre, Annenberg Theatre, Dorothy Chandler Pavilion and a 30-concert tour of Washington with the trio, Aristeia Trio pianist Vijay has won Grand Prizes in the 2016 &lt;em&gt;Classics Alive Artists&lt;/em&gt; competition, 2016 Frances Walton Chamber Music Competition, 2015 Seattle Symphony International Piano Competition and 2008 Los Angeles Music Center’s Spotlight Awards. In 2008 he was named a Davidson Fellow, honored with an award ceremony and reception at the Library of Congress. A 2009 alumnus of NPR’s ‘From the Top’ with host Christopher O’ Riley, and a 2009 Winner of NFAA YoungARTS, he took 1st Prizes in the 2011 Zimmerli International Solo Piano Competition, 2004 San Jose International Piano Competition, 2007 World Piano Pedagogue Competition, and 2nd prize in the 2007 Virginia Waring International Piano Competition. Vijay’s principal professors have included Dr. Sarkis Baltaian, Norman Krieger and Jeffrey Kahane. He is a recipient of the 2015 Parnassus Society Prize, 2014 Birte Moller Young Artist Award, and the 2013 Thornton Music Faculty Award from the University of Southern California graduating as a 2017 Discovery Scholar. He plans to pursue a Masters at Indiana University with professor Norman Krieger as a recipient of the Barbara and David Jacobs Fellowship. He is currently managed by &lt;em&gt;Classics Alive Artists&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annie Jacobs-Perkins&lt;/strong&gt;, known for her intense musicality and “hypnotic lyricism” (Alex Ross, the New Yorker), is a senior Trustee Scholar studying cello performance with Ralph Kirshbaum at USC’s Thornton School of Music and pursuing minors in German Studies and Literature. Annie is the winner of many awards and competitions in her hometown of Rochester, NY. Most recently in 2016, Annie was a member of the youngest ensemble, the Callisto Piano Trio, to win a top prize in senior division of the Fischoff National Chamber Music Competition. In 2014 Annie had two appearances on NPR, once as a soloist on “From the Top” with host Christopher O’Riley and the other on “Air Play.” As a part of the Woodstock Duo with David Steinhardt (guitar and cello), Annie won all age divisions of the Virtuosi Chamber Music Competition, resulting in subsequent radio appearances. The same group recently won Thornton’s prestigious Gluck Fellowship. After sitting principal of the Rochester Philharmonic Youth Orchestra for four consecutive years, at age seventeen Annie was selected to be the associate principal for the New York String Orchestra’s 2014 concerts in Carnegie Hall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In her last year of high school Annie was a volunteer strings teacher at an El Sistema-based, after-school strings program for inner-city students in Rochester. At the same she graduated from high school, Annie obtained a diploma from the Honors Certificate Program at the Hochstein School of Music and Dance under the tutelage of Kathleen Murphy Kemp and Doleen Hood as well as a Pre-Collegiate Diploma in Music Theory from the Eastman Community Music School. In 2015 she won the Thornton School’s Solo Bach Competition and the Burbank Philharmonic’s Hennings-Fischer Young Artist Competition. As a result of the latter, Annie performed Elgar’s Cello Concerto with the Burbank Philharmonic last February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Micah Wright&lt;/strong&gt;, an exciting and versatile young clarinetist, is quickly gaining a following in Southern California and the United States. This year alone, Micah has given solo performances in Honolulu, Nashville, Flint, Santa Barbara, and Thousand Oaks with great success. Micah is the 2nd prize winner of the 2017 Backun International Clarinet Competition, one of five finalists in the 2017 William C. Byrd International Young Artists Competition, winner of the 2016 MTNA California Young Artists Woodwind Competition, and winner of the 2016 Frances Walton Competition. Micah has also received 2nd prize in the 2012 International Woodwind Festival’s Young Artist Competition, and was one of six finalists in the 2012 International Clarinet Association’s Young Artist Competition, and was a 2009 youngARTS winner. Micah won the concerto competition for the world-renowned Shepherd School Symphony in 2011 and has been a featured concerto soloist with the Masterworks Festival Orchestra, Drake University Symphony Orchestra, Des Moines Metro Concert Band, and the Orange County Youth Symphony Orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to his solo playing, Micah is an active chamber musician, orchestral clarinetist, studio musician, and collaborative pianist. Micah is currently the Adjunct Professor of Clarinet and Saxophone at California Lutheran University, maintains a private studio, and gives clinics and masterclasses throughout the Southwest as clinician for D’Addario Woodwinds. Micah received his D.M.A from USC (2015), his M.M. from Rice University (2012), and his B.M. from Drake University (2009) at the age of 19.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Ensemble Caprice</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-23T19:30:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T19:30:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2019-02-23:/ensemble-caprice.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;February 23, 2019 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is an additional &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice-family-program.html"&gt;family performance in …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;February 23, 2019 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is an additional &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice-family-program.html"&gt;family performance in the afternoon&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice-lecture-demonstration.html"&gt;lecture demonstration&lt;/a&gt; on Friday.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthias Maute et Sophie Larivière, recorder &lt;br&gt;
Susie Napper, violoncello &lt;br&gt;
David Jacques, baroque guitar &lt;br&gt;
Ziya Tabassian, percussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ensemblecaprice.com/en/"&gt;Ensemble Caprice website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Main Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Johann Heinrich and Maria&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Johann Heinrich Schmelzer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Serenata con altre arie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(1623-1680)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Serenata-Arlecchino-Adagio-Allegro-Ciacona-Campanella e Lamento&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Biagio and Monica&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Biagio Marini&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sonata sopra la Monica&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Andrea Falconieri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Passacalle (1650)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Carlo Calvi (Italy, 17th century)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aria di Fiorenza y sua Corente (1646)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Anonymus (Rome, 1657)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ciacona di Paradiso, et dell inferno&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Krystof and Ana&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stories of love and solitude&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Anonymous (16th century)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Czech Folk songs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Andrea and his wife&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Johann Heinrich Schmelzer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sonata seconda op.III,3 (1660)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Andrea Falconieri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Battalla de Barabaso yerno de Satanas (1650)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(Intermission)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Johann Sebastian and Maria Barbara&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J.S.Bach (1685-1750)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chaconne BWV 1004 (arr.M.Maute)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Henry and Frances&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Henry Purcell (1659-1696)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Two in one upon a Ground&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Anonymous 17th century&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Duke of Norfolk, or Paul’s Steeple (1684)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Henry Purcell (1659-1696)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A New Scotch Tune&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Anonymous 17th century&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Budro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Santiago and Isabella&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Santiago de Murcia (1673 - 1739)    La Jota&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Antonio, Paula and Ana&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Antonio Vivaldi (1681-1741)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sonate op.I,12 La Follia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;There is an additional &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice-family-program.html"&gt;family performance in the afternoon&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice-lecture-demonstration.html"&gt;lecture demonstration&lt;/a&gt; on Friday.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensemble Caprice has been hailed by the New York Times as “an ensemble, that encourages the listener to rehear the world”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In 2019 the Caprice will celebrate its 30th anniversary!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded by acclaimed conductor, composer and recorder soloist Matthias Maute, Ensemble Caprice has become known for its innovative and adventuresome approach to an increasingly expanding musical repertoire on period instruments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to its series of concerts in Montreal, the group tours extensively, giving dozens of concerts in Quebec, Canada, the USA, Europe, and even Asia. The ensemble is a regular guest at many prestigious European festivals: the Lufthansa Festival of Baroque Music in London, the Bruges (Belgium) and Utrecht (Netherlands) festivals, the Felicia Blumenthal International Music Festival in Tel Aviv; and in Germany, the Musikfestspiele Potsdam Sanssouci, the Regensburg Early Music Festival, the Händel-Festspiele in Halle, and the Stockstadt festival. The New York Times published a lengthy article hailing the musicians’ innovative and refreshing approach, praising them as “imaginative (and) powerful; the playing is top-flight”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ensemble’s recording activity is every bit as impressive: Their CDs have gained many honors and much critical acclaim. The CD Gloria! Vivaldi and his Angels received a JUNO Award and three prestigious Prix Opus awards. Ensemble Caprice was also recognized for its artistic approach and the quality of its performances by being selected “People’s choice and was a finalist in the music category for the Montreal Arts Council’s Grand Prix de Montréal. The group also earned a nomination for the Echo Klassic award in Germany and the acclaimed publication Gramophone Magazine chose the group’s CD Telemann and the Baroque Gypsies as one of its recommended recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015 and 2016 the ensemble went twice to China and represented Canada at the festival Meet in Beijing. In 2017 the Ensemble will be touring in Central America, South America and again in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensemble Caprice produces videos for the website noncerto which promote classical music in a new way. The videos have been viewed in more than 150 countries around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the USA the CD Chaconne-Voices of Eternity has been selected CD of the year 2016 by Radio WBRB in Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ensemble Caprice is supported by the Conseil des arts et des lettres du Québec&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=" " class="floatleft" src="https://cameratamusica.com/images/2018-2019/calq-logo.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Ensemble Caprice Family Program</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice-family-program.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-23T16:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2019-02-23:/ensemble-caprice-family-program.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;February 23, 2019 4:00 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This performance is in addition to the …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;February 23, 2019 4:00 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This performance is in addition to the &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice.html"&gt;evening performance&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice-lecture-demonstration.html"&gt;lecture demonstration&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthias Maute et Sophie Larivière, recorder &lt;br&gt;
Susie Napper, violoncello &lt;br&gt;
David Jacques, baroque guitar &lt;br&gt;
Ziya Tabassian, percussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ensemblecaprice.com/en/"&gt;Ensemble Caprice website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Family Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A baroque feast: Music and stories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music tells stories. What is the story hidden behind J.H.Schmelzer’s &lt;em&gt;Serenata con altre arie&lt;/em&gt; or A.Vivaldi’s &lt;em&gt;La Follia&lt;/em&gt;? Ensemble Caprice performs and tells musical stories which reach out to us today throughout the centuries. The program &lt;strong&gt;A baroque feast&lt;/strong&gt; celebrates the magic of music!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event is ideal for parents and children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no admission charge.  First-come, first-seated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This performance is in addition to the &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice.html"&gt;evening performance&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice-lecture-demonstration.html"&gt;lecture demonstration&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensemble Caprice has been hailed by the New York Times as “an ensemble, that encourages the listener to rehear the world”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In 2019 the Caprice will celebrate its 30th anniversary!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded by acclaimed conductor, composer and recorder soloist Matthias Maute, Ensemble Caprice has become known for its innovative and adventuresome approach to an increasingly expanding musical repertoire on period instruments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to its series of concerts in Montreal, the group tours extensively, giving dozens of concerts in Quebec, Canada, the USA, Europe, and even Asia. The ensemble is a regular guest at many prestigious European festivals: the Lufthansa Festival of Baroque Music in London, the Bruges (Belgium) and Utrecht (Netherlands) festivals, the Felicia Blumenthal International Music Festival in Tel Aviv; and in Germany, the Musikfestspiele Potsdam Sanssouci, the Regensburg Early Music Festival, the Händel-Festspiele in Halle, and the Stockstadt festival. The New York Times published a lengthy article hailing the musicians’ innovative and refreshing approach, praising them as “imaginative (and) powerful; the playing is top-flight”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ensemble’s recording activity is every bit as impressive: Their CDs have gained many honors and much critical acclaim. The CD Gloria! Vivaldi and his Angels received a JUNO Award and three prestigious Prix Opus awards. Ensemble Caprice was also recognized for its artistic approach and the quality of its performances by being selected “People’s choice and was a finalist in the music category for the Montreal Arts Council’s Grand Prix de Montréal. The group also earned a nomination for the Echo Klassic award in Germany and the acclaimed publication Gramophone Magazine chose the group’s CD Telemann and the Baroque Gypsies as one of its recommended recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015 and 2016 the ensemble went twice to China and represented Canada at the festival Meet in Beijing. In 2017 the Ensemble will be touring in Central America, South America and again in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensemble Caprice produces videos for the website noncerto which promote classical music in a new way. The videos have been viewed in more than 150 countries around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the USA the CD Chaconne-Voices of Eternity has been selected CD of the year 2016 by Radio WBRB in Boston.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Ensemble Caprice Lecture Demonstration</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice-lecture-demonstration.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-23T16:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T16:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2019-02-23:/ensemble-caprice-lecture-demonstration.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;February 22, 2019 11:00 am at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ensemble Caprice Artist Director Matthias Maute&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;February 22, 2019 11:00 am at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ensemble Caprice Artist Director Matthias Maute&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Columbia Basin College Arts Center is pleased to announce that Ensemble Caprice Artist Director Matthias Maute will be presenting a lecture demonstration on Friday, February 22, from 11AM to 12PM, in the CBC Theatre.  He will be providing a solo demonstration and lecture as an introduction to the upcoming concerts on Saturday, February 23.  There will also be time for a Q &amp;amp; A for those attending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a wonderful opportunity to hear this gifted artist speak about his work with Ensemble Caprice and the literature he focuses on, as well as, answer questions.  This lecture demonstration is brought to you through the partnership formed between Camerata Music and the CBC Arts Center.  The public is welcome and this event is offered free of charge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ensemblecaprice.com/en/"&gt;Ensemble Caprice website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;This performance is in addition to the &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice.html"&gt;evening performance&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://cameratamusica.com/ensemble-caprice-family-program.html"&gt;family concert&lt;/a&gt; on Saturday, February 23rd&lt;/h3&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Maxwell Quartet</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/maxwell-quartet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-26T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2019-01-26:/maxwell-quartet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;January 26, 2019 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colin Scobie, 1st violin &lt;br&gt;
George Smith, 2nd …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;January 26, 2019 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colin Scobie, 1st violin &lt;br&gt;
George Smith, 2nd violin &lt;br&gt;
Elliot Perks, viola &lt;br&gt;
Duncan Strachan, cello&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.maxwellstringquartet.com/"&gt;Maxwell Quartet website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franz Josepf Haydn (1732-1809) &lt;br&gt;
String Quartet in E-flat major, Op.71 no. 3, Apponyi, Hob.III:71&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joey Roukens (b.1982) &lt;br&gt;
Visions at Sea (2011)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scottish Folk Music (to be announced from the stage)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(intermission)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ludwig van Beethoven (1770-1827) &lt;br&gt;
Quartet in B-flat major, Op.130&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Maxwell Quartet appears by arrangement with Lisa Sapinkopf Artists, &lt;a href="www.chambermuse.com"&gt;www.chambermuse.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1st Prize winner and Audience Prize winner at the Trondheim (Norway) International Chamber Music Competition in 2017, the Maxwell Quartet has been hailed for "great communication" by The Strad Magazine and as “brilliantly fresh, unexpected and exhilarating” by The Scottish Herald. The Glasgow-based Maxwell Quartet is now firmly regarded as one of Britain's finest string quartets, with a strong connection to their folk music heritage and a commitment to bringing together wide-ranging projects and programmes to expand the string quartet repertoire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quartet performs regularly across the UK and abroad, at venues including London’s Wigmore Hall, Purcell Room, St Martin-in-the-Fields, and the BBC Chamber Music Proms. Their 2017-18 season includes engagements in Denmark, Norway, Germany, the Netherlands, France and China. Their first North American tour, in January 2019, is to coincide with the release of their début CD, featuring works by Haydn and traditional Scottish folk music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Maxwell Quartet consists of four great friends who grew up playing classical and folk music together in youth orchestras and music schools across Scotland. The group officially began in 2010 at the Royal Conservatoire of Scotland, where its founding members met as postgraduate students. The very next year, the Quartet was appointed as the Conservatoire's Young Artists in Residence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performing widely across Scotland, the quartet has established a reputation for delighting audiences with their "unnaffected enthusiasm" (North Highland Times) and their "panache and conviction" (Strathearn Herald). The quartet has held residencies at Oxford University, Perth Concert Hall and many chamber music festivals across the UK, including their own Loch Shiel Festival in the Scottish highlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passionate about collaborating with other musicians and art forms, the quartet has worked with world-renowned pianists Benjamin Grosvenor and Jeremy Menuhin as well as a global roster of artists and institutions including Cryptic Theatre, the experimental performance space Wintour’s Leap, the Royal Ballet School, the Scottish-German soul duo Lunir, cinematographer Herman Kolgen, and many more. They have also commissioned works by some of the UK's most dynamic composers including Anna Meredith, Tom Harrold, Mark Simpson and Colin Broom. The quartet regularly broadcasts on BBC Radio Scotland, as well as giving school workshops and children's concerts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Maxwell Quartet was mentored by the Endellion Quartet at King's Place, London, and studied privately with Hatto Beyerle, founding member of the Alban Berg Quartet, in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Haydn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although commissioned by Count Apponyi, a good violinist and generous patron of the arts, this quartet was actually written in preparation for Haydn's second trip to London, and the violinist more on Haydn's mind was surely the London impresario Johann Peter Salomon. So the work incorporates several of the tricks Haydn developed to impress (or, in the beginning, subdue) his English audiences. The first movement, for instance, begins with what László Somfai memorably called a "noise-killer curtain," one loud, attention-getting chord separated from the main Vivace material by a full bar's rest. Another London trick is the series of unusual-for the time, almost freakish-modulations in the development section that veer from the sonata-form movement's standard harmonic path. The movement's witty first theme spins along happily for four bars before stopping to check itself with two quiet, bouncy little measures, and continues to repeat that pattern. The second subject is a slippery canon that never quite fires its contrapuntal shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Andante con moto is a set of free variations on two themes, one an informal major-mode humming tune, and the other a minor-mode subject closely related to the first. The two are so similar, in fact, that it can be difficult to determine which is being varied-or if the second theme itself is simply a minor variation on the first. The movement's most notable moment comes in the third variation, in which the often-neglected cello gets the leading voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if emboldened by his cello solo in the slow movement, Haydn allots a brief solo to each instrument in his lengthy Minuet, as if the momentarily dominant player were making a quiet confession to the others. The central trio begins deep in the solo cello, and by the end has risen to a violin part placed well above the staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final movement, Vivace, takes ternary form, with the loping outer sections looking ahead to the Viennese waltz. The middle portion is a mild fugato in which Haydn shows off to the Londoners his superior Teutonic technique. —James Reel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roukens:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joey Roukens was born in Schiedam, the Netherlands, in 1982. He studied composition with Klaas de Vries at the Rotterdam Conservatory and psychology at Leiden University. His works have been performed by major ensembles and soloists in the Netherlands and abroad, such as the Royal Concertgebouw Orchestra, the Netherlands Philharmonic Orchestra, the New York Philharmonic, the Orchestra dell’Accademia Nazionale di Santa Cecilia, Britten Sinfonia, and Tokyo Sinfonietta. For a long time, Roukens has also been active in pop music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roukens strives to move away from modernist ways of thinking in search for a more eclectic and direct idiom. He seeks to organically integrate elements from highly diverse influences and aesthetics, and thus doesn’t shy away from the use of tonality, references to popular music, vernacular culture, "stealing" from the musical heritage of the past, and the odd trivial turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visions at Sea&lt;/em&gt; explores the turbulent voyages that Dutch seafarers made in the 17th century. It uses old Dutch sea shanties carefully woven into a dynamic framework which lurches from moments of serene beauty to ones of wild frenzy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beethoven:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beethoven's last string quartets were composed during the final years of his life between 1824 and 1826. The project began with a commission from the Russian Prince Nicholas Galitzin, an amateur cellist who requested "one, two or three" string quartets. Once Beethoven began work in earnest, he turned out five massive quartets that ultimately become six separate works known simply and profoundly as "The Late Quartets." For decades, these quartets were regarded by most as quite possibly the work of a once great composer now degenerated into a deafness and insanity. (Schubert, Mendelssohn and Schumann thought differently). It was not until the 20th century that the late quartets became widely regarded as profound and transcendent masterworks worthy of entering, if not becoming, the apex of the traditional repertoire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third of the late quartets in the order Beethoven composed them, Op.130 was completed in November of 1825. Beethoven and his publisher surprisingly agreed that the finale did not sit well with the rest of the quartet movements. The bristling fugue of epic proportions was deemed "too much" for audiences of the time, and it was detached and published as a separate opus. Beethoven composed a fresh, much lighter finale to complete Op. 130 in its revised, final version. The quartet will be performed tonight in its original version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like nearly all of the Beethoven's late quartets, Op.130 can be approached in many ways. Without regard to the well-established elite tradition of quartet form, style and expression, Op.130 presents a surface beauty, technical facility and rich emotional aspect that can't fail to strike a casual listener as truly lovely music with profound tendencies. But seen within a framework of traditional works by Haydn and Mozart, Op.130 is, like the other late quartets, a very odd and possibly incomprehensible departure. Herein lies one sense of the term "difficult" applied to these late works: "difficult to follow" compared to the rhetorical conventions of the time. But surely another meaning behind the term "difficult" is the emotional demands they make they induce in the listener. Throughout the late quartets, one finds extreme emotional states that can, at times, be difficult because they are simply so intense and effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Op.130, particularly in its original form, is truly an anomaly from a conventional perspective. Rather than the traditional four movements, it has six. Of these, two are almost laughably short while the original fugal finale was outrageously long and truly "difficult" in every sense of the word. The fourth movement is a triple meter German dance with a trio of a rustic character, but the second movement is also clearly a scherzo of ternary design. Two scherzi? Although the opening movement appears to be in a rather straightforward sonata form (it is far more), the fifth movement is a basic operatic cavatina of surprisingly simple design with an indescribably haunting character nonetheless. The musicologist Michael Steinberg suggests that to the listeners of the day, this must have seemed like a miscellany of movements, more like a divertimento or suite than a string quartet. Musicologist Leonard Ratner provides a convincing analysis that Beethoven was indeed intentionally invoking an antique form of suite complete with Renaissance canzona, a march, an aria and a gigue, a design that practically renders the Grosse Fuge an inextricable part of a grand design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this only reinforces the essential fact that Beethoven was an undaunted pioneer and artistic visionary who created, particularly in the late quartets, truly complicated works of high art that speak on many levels lending themselves to multiple if not infinite interpretations and reactions. They are indescribably compelling works that have mesmerized players, composers, scholars, poets and avid listeners for nearly two hundred years. Perhaps one of their most essential traits is that they can become as "difficult" as one wishes or, miraculously, as direct, simple and obvious as one's willingness to hear and feel. Feel and "understand" them as you can and as you will. It is a project worthy of a lifetime. —Kai Christiansen&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Frisson</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/frisson.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2018-11-17:/frisson.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;November 17, 2018 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Kennewick+First+Presbyterian+Church"&gt;Kennewick First Presbyterian Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adelya Nartadjieva, violin &lt;br&gt;
Caeli Smith, viola and Associate Director …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;November 17, 2018 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Kennewick+First+Presbyterian+Church"&gt;Kennewick First Presbyterian Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adelya Nartadjieva, violin &lt;br&gt;
Caeli Smith, viola and Associate Director &lt;br&gt;
Julian Schwarz, cello &lt;br&gt;
Sam Suggs, bass &lt;br&gt;
Ji Weon Ryu, flute &lt;br&gt;
Thomas Gallant, oboe and Artistic Director &lt;br&gt;
Bixby Kennedy, clarinet &lt;br&gt;
Rémy Taghavi, bassoon &lt;br&gt;
Eric Huckins, French horn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://frissonensemble.com/"&gt;Frisson website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Divertimento in C Major for viola oboe and bass&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Michael Haydn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Allegro molto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1737-1806&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aria&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Menuetto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Andante&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Octet for strings and winds Op. 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;August Walter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Allegro moderato&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1821-1896&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scherzo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Finale – Vivace&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(intermission)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Off Pist&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Svante Henryson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;b. 1956&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bachianas Brasileiros No. 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hector Villa-Lobos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aria (Chôro)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1887-1955&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fantasia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nonet No. 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bohuslav Martinů&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Poco allegro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1890-1959&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Allegretto&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frisson is an explosive group of rising classical stars who are the best of the recent graduates of the top music schools, including Juilliard, Curtis and Yale. Led by Artistic Director and oboist Thomas Gallant, the musicians were chosen through auditions, and the group already has an impressive tour schedule this season including upcoming debuts in New York City and at the Bermuda Festival.  The members of the group all have impressive bios and many have already performed at such prestigious venues as the Verbier, Aspen, Marlboro, and Ravinia Festivals as well as at Carnegie Hall and Lincoln Center’s David Geffen Hall.  Frisson programs include music with different combinations of strings and winds, and the core group of violin, viola, cello, bass, flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon and horn perform such works as the Beethoven Septet, Prokoviev Quintet, Schubert Octet and the Martinu Octet.  Frisson also expands into a larger group for performances of the complete Brandenburg Concerti as well as a small chamber orchestra for symphonies of Haydn and Mozart.  Frisson is based in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Byrd Ensemble</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/the-byrd-ensemble-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2018-10-27:/the-byrd-ensemble-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;October 27, 2018 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SOPRANO &lt;br&gt;
Ruth Schauble &lt;br&gt;
Margaret Obenza &lt;br&gt;
Christina Siemens …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;October 27, 2018 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SOPRANO &lt;br&gt;
Ruth Schauble &lt;br&gt;
Margaret Obenza &lt;br&gt;
Christina Siemens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALTO &lt;br&gt;
Sarra Sharif &lt;br&gt;
Joshua Haberman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TENOR &lt;br&gt;
Orrin Doyle &lt;br&gt;
Kurt Kruckeberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BASS &lt;br&gt;
Willimark Obenza &lt;br&gt;
Kevin Wyatt &lt;br&gt;
Clayton Moser&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DIRECTOR &lt;br&gt;
Markdavin Obenza&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.byrdensemble.com/"&gt;The Byrd Ensemble Web Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MUSICAL POLITICS: Motets of Influence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ne irascaris&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;William Byrd&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c. 1540-1623&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;To Morning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gabriel Jackson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;b. 1962&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gaude gloriosa&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thomas Tallis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c. 1505-1585&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(intermission)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Miserere&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gregorio Allegri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c. 1582-1625&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Woman with the Alabaster Box&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Avro Pärt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;b. 1935&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tribue Domine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;William Byrd&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c. 1540-1623&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musicians&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sacred music generally served a liturgical purpose, and often also a &lt;em&gt;political&lt;/em&gt; one. Whether it was Tallis and Byrd dedicating large collections of motets to the Queen in return for a monopoly on music printing rights, or the music from Tallis’s &lt;em&gt;Gaude gloriosa&lt;/em&gt; used as a battle rallying cry when the King was at war with France, each piece on the program comes with an interesting story and gives us a peek into the composers’ allegiances and a sense of the intertwined religious and political turbulence of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Described as “pure and radiant” (Gramophone), “immensely impressive” (Early Music Review), and “rich, full-voiced, and perfectly blended” (Early Music America), the Byrd Ensemble is garnering international acclaim for its performances and recordings of chamber vocal music, particularly Renaissance polyphony. The Byrd Ensemble, directed by Markdavin Obenza, is a Seattle-based professional ensemble made up of 10 to 12 singers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2004, the ensemble has performed in the greater Seattle area and has toured across the United States, presenting concerts for the Gotham Early Music Scene in New York with Peter Phillips (director of the Tallis Scholars) and the Boston Early Music Fringe Series. In 2014, the Byrd Ensemble was one of sixteen groups—the only ensemble from the United States—chosen to sing at the London International A Cappella Choir Competition and worked with Peter Phillips, Mark Williams, and John Rutter, who described the ensemble as “a fine group that has achieved an enviable standard of tuning, blend, and ensemble.” The group presents an annual subscription series at St. James Cathedral in Seattle and regularly performs in Portland, Oregon. The Byrd Ensemble is a nonprofit organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Byrd Ensemble became part of the Scribe Records label in 2011 and has since produced six records—four of which feature Renaissance polyphony— and have been reviewed by major early music publications: &lt;em&gt;Early Music America, Gramophone, and Early Music Review. Our Lady: Music from the Peterhouse Partbooks&lt;/em&gt; (2011) featured reconstructions by musicologist Nick Sandon of music by lesser-known English Renaissance composers—Pasche, Merbecke, and Ludford—and included two world-premiere recordings. &lt;em&gt;In the Company of William Byrd&lt;/em&gt; (2012), &lt;em&gt;Music for the Tudors&lt;/em&gt; (2015), and &lt;em&gt;Music of the Renaissance: Italy, England &amp;amp; France&lt;/em&gt; (2016) featured more mainstream Renaissance composers Tallis, Sheppard, Byrd, and White. The Byrd Ensemble's recording of Estonian composer Arvo Pärt appeared in the international edition of Gramophone Magazine in 2014 and recently in French film &lt;em&gt;L'apparition&lt;/em&gt; (2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARTISTIC DIRECTOR MARKDAVIN OBENZA has dedicated his career to music. In addition to the Byrd Ensemble, Markdavin is also Director and founder of Seattle-based chamber choir Vox16 and Producer for Scribe Records, an independent record label. He is an active freelance singer who performs with the Byrd Ensemble and has performed with the Tudor Choir, Early Music Vancouver, and members of the Tallis Scholars. He is the Director of Choral Music at Trinity Parish Church in Seattle, WA.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Jovanni-Rey de Pedro</title><link href="https://cameratamusica.com/jovanni-rey-de-pedro.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-22T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colin Brislawn</name></author><id>tag:cameratamusica.com,2018-09-22:/jovanni-rey-de-pedro.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h4&gt;September 22, 2018 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jdepedro.com/"&gt;Jovanni-Rey de Pedro website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STRAUSS II …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;September 22, 2018 7:30 pm at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/BZDawJuNMRM2"&gt;Columbia Basin College, Performing Arts Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jdepedro.com/"&gt;Jovanni-Rey de Pedro website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STRAUSS II/DOHNANYI
&lt;em&gt;Schatzwalzer&lt;/em&gt; from "Der Zigeunerbaron"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F. HAYDN
Sonata in E-flat, Hob. 52&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F. GULDA
Variations on “Light My Fire”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(intermission)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T. LESCHETIZSKY
Andante Finale from Lucia di Lammermoor, for Left Hand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S. RACHMANINOFF
Sonata in B-flat minor, Op. 36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the Musician&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filipino-American pianist &lt;strong&gt;Jovanni-Rey V. de Pedro&lt;/strong&gt; has developed an international reputation as a soloist, collaborator, pedagogue, speaker, entrepreneur, and philanthropist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from a family of musicians whose musical heritage dates back more than a century, Jovanni has appeared to public acclaim in recital and academic venues on five continents  including London’s St. Martin-in-the-Fields, Weill Recital Hall at Carnegie Hall in New York, the Eroica-Saal in Vienna, and the Irish World Academy of Music and Dance. Jovanni has received numerous prizes in competitions in the United States, Canada, Spain, England, Austria, and Greece, including the Isabelle Bond Gold Medal for Performance Excellence, first place at the Pacific International Competition, and second place at the Ibiza International Competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jovanni’s academic research and pedagogical interests have led to presentations for the Music Teachers National Association (MTNA) and its state and local affiliates, the College Music Society (CMS), and the European Piano Teachers Association/World Piano Teachers Association in Serbia. He has also been featured as a keynote speaker and recitalist for the Australasian Piano Pedagogy Conference, and the Music Teachers Association of Queensland’s Alan Lane Memorial Workshops in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recipient of the 2017 Steinway Top Teacher Award, Jovanni's mission as a pedagogue is to develop pianists and teachers who are intelligent, creative, disciplined, reflective, and communicative. In addition to helping students reach their full potential as sensitive musicians, he is passionate about the growth of professional skills. In 2012, he received national recognition for spearheading the formation of the Piano Pedagogy Symposium, a conference by college students for college students. This MTNA event has since brought together hundreds of young music professionals to share creative ideas, network, and develop skills as scholars, presenters, thinkers, performers, entrepreneurs, and teachers. Jovanni is also a founding member of the Young Professionals Track at the MTNA National Conference, and currently serves as in MTNA’s Special Committee on Young Professionals and committees for the National Conference on Keyboard Pedagogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it be collaborating with engineers to perform at a University of Idaho football game on a spinning piano with the Vandal Marching Band, or teaming up with Millsaps College’s award-winning community service program to bring piano lessons to adults from impoverished areas of Jackson, Jovanni can be continuously seen seeking ways to reach a wider audience, further music and music education, and give back to the community. Over the years, he has helped raise more than $100,000 for dozens of civic and religious organizations such as the Alay Sa Kabataan (Gift of the Children) Foundation in the Philippines, the Filipino Catholic Chaplaincy of Vienna, Grace House Mississippi, and the Austrian-American Council West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A California native and alumni of the Los Angeles County High School for the Arts (LACHSA), Jovanni holds a Diplom (with auszeichnung) from the Vienna Conservatory’s Konzertfach Abteilung in Austria where his studies were supported by the ASCAP/Leiber &amp;amp; Stoller Foundations. He received a Master of Music degree in Performance Studies from Trinity College of Music in London, and earned a Doctor of Musical Arts degree in Piano Pedagogy and Performance from the University of Michigan (Go Blue!). After teaching appointments at Millsaps College in Mississippi, Levine School of Music in Washington D.C., and the University of Idaho, Jovanni joined the faculty at Samford University’s School of the Arts as Assistant Professor of Piano and Piano Pedagogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now a mentor to his own students, “Dr. J” is grateful for his teachers and people who have positively impacted his life - namely his parents (his dad was his first piano teacher), Gloria Ho-Sims, Vilma Posadas, Robert Ward, Gerhard Geretschläger, Aries Caces, Yonty Solomon, Mikhail Kazakevich, Deniz Arman Gelenbe, Louis Nagel, and John Ellis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, please visit &lt;a href="www.jdepedro.com"&gt;www.jdepedro.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>